# ANA JIMENEZ

Reservations Executive



anajimezg@gmail.com



www.anajimezg.com



linkedin.com/in/anajimezgg



087 172 8127

Versatile technical **translator** with experience in **project management**, **hospitality** and **customer service** who is passionate about **tech efficiency** and **digitalisation**.

A resourceful and highly motivated individual, with strong **storytelling**, **communication** and **organization** skills.

**Customer-centric, compassionate** and **solution-oriented**, both critically and creatively, excelling in tailored customer support.



WORK EXPERIENCE

### HOSPITALITY INDUTRY

RESERVATIONS EXECUTIVE

RECEPTIONIST

**Grafton & Chancery | May 2023 - Present** 

Dalata Hotel Group | Oct 2022 - May 2023

#### ORACLE - OPERA CLOUD INTEGRATION

- Created meaningful relationships with customers by providing tailored and empathetic support, troubleshooting any tricky scenario that may arise, and resulting in <u>delighted customers</u>.
- Provided 100+ customised quotation proposals for corporate and leisure group clients demonstrating resourcefulness, proficiency in B2B negotiation and adaptability to evolving requirements.
- Conducted daily data-driven analytics and reporting, including preparation of <u>Pick-up and Pace</u> Reports, to identify new challenges and trends and developed critical lines of action to address them.
- Managed 50+ client accounts (through <u>Rate Code Configuration</u>) across multiple platforms e.g. *Oracle, Booking.com, SynXis.*
- Championed and implemented features for efficiency and reliability of OTA third-party integrations and reported directly to Commercial Director, resolving time-sensitive client issues resulting in direct boost in revenue.

### FREELANCE CONSULTANT & TRANSLATOR

PROJECT COORDINATION

Aug 2019 - Aug 2022

#### PROJECT COORDINATION [AGILE METHODOLOGY]

- Enhanced my entrepreneurial and managerial skills through active involvement in the conception, development, execution, and translation of transnational e-Learning initiatives, whilst concurrently overseeing a parallel client base.
- Partnered with 40+ EU organisations and institutions 'to develop, transfer and/or implement innovative practices at organisational, local, regional, national and European levels.'
- Contributed to initiatives aiming to create a fairer and more sustainable, accessible and inclusive environment for communities and individuals across the EU.
- Took charge of planning and coordinating online and in-person international meetings. My responsibilities encompassed researching and implementing cost-efficient logistics, offering support as needed, and maintaining meticulous accounting records.
- Held comprehensive oversight over concurrent projects, ensuring they met predetermined metrics and objectives, whilst continuously evaluating and improving collaborations.
- Developed a deep understanding of Project Management and associated methodologies.
- Successfully coordinated 6 projects simultaneously.

#### TECHNICAL TRANSLATOR

#### Aug 2019 - Aug 2022

#### CAT TOOLS - SDL TRADOS

- Helped 50+ businesses and individuals to reach wider audiences for their products that included legal documents, website content, news articles, and corporate reports.
- Focused on technical translation, working hand in hand with key players of social change at the European level.
- Won and contributed to 8 transnational projects.
- Partnered with 40+ organisations operating internationally.
- Broadened my skill-set to include coordination of multilingual translation projects across 5 countries.
- Work completed was both fiscally and socially impactful.

### **CUSTOMER SERVICE & TECHNICAL SUPPORT**

CUSTOMER SERVICE

Feb 2018 - Jul 2019

#### PARKING MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS - EQUINSA, SKIDATA

- Remotely managed operations across 60+ car parks nationwide, utilising diverse operating systems and varied communication channels.
- Demonstrated strong multitasking abilities for competing priorities and swiftly resolved technical issues in a high-demanding environment.
- Quickly mastered infrastructure management solution for continued maintenance and functioning.
- Proficiency in time-sensitive problem-solving for real-time incident-response.

EDUCATION



TRANSLATION AND INTERPRETING

Universidad Pablo de Olavide (Sevilla) | 2011 - 2016

LANGUES ÉTRANGÈRES APPLIQUÉES

Université Paris-Sorbonne (Paris) | 2013 - 2014



### SKILLS & LANGUAGES

- Spanish ★★★★★
- English ★★★★★
- French ★★★

- Content creation
- Strategy & planning
- Troubleshooting

- Tech-Savvy
- Team work
- Determination

## PASSIONS & CONTRIBUTIONS



- Yoga
- Cross-Training
- Culinary Arts
- Self-development \*
- Travel 🛪
- Cats

- Worked towards woman empowerment and gender equality in disadvantageous contexts. ☑
- Participated in award-winning projects with both fiscal, resulting in further funding, and societal, aiding children at risk, impact. ☑ ☑
- Volunteered with Red Cross to provide English education to communities in need in Ceuta.
- Volunteered with a <u>soup kitchen</u> developing accessible content for wider reach to all communities in need.